<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<permission-info>
    <string name="permlab_statusBar">disable or modify status bar</string>
    <string name="permdesc_statusBar">Allows the app to disable the status bar or add and remove system icons.</string>
    <string name="permlab_statusBarService">status bar</string>
    <string name="permdesc_statusBarService">Allows the app to be the status bar.</string>
    <string name="permlab_expandStatusBar">expand/collapse status bar</string>
    <string name="permdesc_expandStatusBar">Allows the app to expand or collapse the status bar.</string>
    <string name="permlab_install_shortcut">install shortcuts</string>
    <string name="permdesc_install_shortcut">Allows an application to add
        Homescreen shortcuts without user intervention.</string>
    <string name="permlab_uninstall_shortcut">uninstall shortcuts</string>
    <string name="permdesc_uninstall_shortcut">Allows the application to remove
        Homescreen shortcuts without user intervention.</string>
    <string name="permlab_processOutgoingCalls">reroute outgoing calls</string>
    <string name="permdesc_processOutgoingCalls">Allows the app to see the
        number being dialed during an outgoing call with the option to redirect
        the call to a different number or abort the call altogether.</string>
    <string name="permlab_receiveSms">receive text messages (SMS)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_receiveSms">Allows the app to receive and process SMS
      messages. This means the app could monitor or delete messages sent to your
      device without showing them to you.</string>
    <string name="permlab_receiveMms">receive text messages (MMS)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_receiveMms">Allows the app to receive and process MMS
      messages. This means the app could monitor or delete messages sent to your
      device without showing them to you.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readCellBroadcasts">read cell broadcast messages</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readCellBroadcasts">Allows the app to read
        cell broadcast messages received by your device. Cell broadcast alerts
        are delivered in some locations to warn you of emergency situations.
        Malicious apps may interfere with the performance or operation of your
        device when an emergency cell broadcast is received.</string>
    <string name="permlab_subscribedFeedsRead">read subscribed feeds</string>
    <string name="permdesc_subscribedFeedsRead">Allows the app to get details about the currently synced feeds.</string>
    <string name="permlab_sendSms">send and view SMS messages</string>
    <string name="permdesc_sendSms">Allows the app to send SMS messages.
     This may result in unexpected charges. Malicious apps may cost you money by
     sending messages without your confirmation.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readSms">read your text messages (SMS or MMS)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readSms">Allows the app to read SMS
      messages stored on your phone or SIM card. This allows the app to read all
      SMS messages, regardless of content or confidentiality.</string>
    <string name="permlab_receiveWapPush">receive text messages (WAP)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_receiveWapPush">Allows the app to receive and process
     WAP messages.  This permission includes the ability to monitor or delete
     messages sent to you without showing them to you.</string>
    <string name="permlab_getTasks">retrieve running apps</string>
    <string name="permdesc_getTasks">Allows the app to retrieve information
       about currently and recently running tasks.  This may allow the app to
       discover information about which applications are used on the device.</string>
    <string name="permlab_manageProfileAndDeviceOwners">Manage profile and device owners</string>
    <string name="permdesc_manageProfileAndDeviceOwners">Allows apps to set the profile owners and the device owner.</string>
    <string name="permlab_reorderTasks">reorder running apps</string>
    <string name="permdesc_reorderTasks">Allows the app to move tasks to the
      foreground and background.  The app may do this without your input.</string>
    <string name="permlab_enableCarMode">enable car mode</string>
    <string name="permdesc_enableCarMode">Allows the app to
        enable the car mode.</string>
    <string name="permlab_killBackgroundProcesses">close other apps</string>
    <string name="permdesc_killBackgroundProcesses">Allows the app to end
      background processes of other apps.  This may cause other apps to stop
      running.</string>
    <string name="permlab_systemAlertWindow">draw over other apps</string>
    <string name="permdesc_systemAlertWindow">Allows the app to draw on top of other
        applications or parts of the user interface.  They may interfere with your
        use of the interface in any application, or change what you think you are
        seeing in other applications.</string>
    <string name="permlab_persistentActivity">make app always run</string>
    <string name="permdesc_persistentActivity">Allows the app to make parts of itself persistent in memory.  This can limit memory available to other apps slowing down the phone.</string>
    <string name="permlab_getPackageSize">measure app storage space</string>
    <string name="permdesc_getPackageSize">Allows the app to retrieve its code, data, and cache sizes</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeSettings">modify system settings</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeSettings">Allows the app to modify the
        system\'s settings data. Malicious apps may corrupt your system\'s
        configuration.</string>
    <string name="permlab_receiveBootCompleted">run at startup</string>
    <string name="permdesc_receiveBootCompleted">Allows the app to
        have itself started as soon as the system has finished booting.
        This can make it take longer to start the phone and allow the
        app to slow down the overall phone by always running.</string>
    <string name="permlab_broadcastSticky">send sticky broadcast</string>
    <string name="permdesc_broadcastSticky">Allows the app to
    send sticky broadcasts, which remain after the broadcast ends. Excessive
    use may make the phone slow or unstable by causing it to use too
    much memory.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readContacts">read your contacts</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readContacts">Allows the app to
      read data about your contacts stored on your phone, including the
      frequency with which you\'ve called, emailed, or communicated in other ways
      with specific individuals. This permission allows apps to save your
      contact data, and malicious apps may share contact data without your
      knowledge.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeContacts">modify your contacts</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeContacts">Allows the app to
    modify the data about your contacts stored on your phone, including the
    frequency with which you\'ve called, emailed, or communicated in other ways
    with specific contacts. This permission allows apps to delete contact
    data.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readCallLog">read call log</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readCallLog">Allows the app to read
      your phone\'s call log, including data about incoming and outgoing calls.
      This permission allows apps to save your call log data, and malicious apps
      may share call log data without your knowledge.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeCallLog">write call log</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeCallLog">Allows the app to modify your phone\'s call log, including data about incoming and outgoing calls.
        Malicious apps may use this to erase or modify your call log.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bodySensors">body sensors (like heart rate monitors)
    </string>
    <string name="permdesc_bodySensors">Allows the app to access data from sensors
    that monitor your physical condition, such as your heart rate.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readCalendar">read calendar events plus confidential information</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readCalendar">Allows the app to
       read all calendar events stored on your phone, including those of friends
       or co-workers. This may allow the app to share or save your calendar data,
       regardless of confidentiality or sensitivity.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeCalendar">add or modify calendar events and send email to guests without owners\' knowledge</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeCalendar">Allows the app to
        add, remove, change events that you can modify on your phone, including
        those of friends or co-workers. This may allow the app to send messages
        that appear to come from calendar owners, or modify events without the
        owners\' knowledge.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessLocationExtraCommands">access extra location provider commands</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessLocationExtraCommands">Allows the app to access
        extra location provider commands.  This may allow the app to interfere
        with the operation of the GPS or other location sources.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessFineLocation">precise location (GPS and
      network-based)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessFineLocation">Allows the app to get your
      precise location using the Global Positioning System (GPS) or network
      location sources such as cell towers and Wi-Fi. These location services
      must be turned on and available to your device for the app to use them.
      Apps may use this to determine where you are, and may consume additional
      battery power.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessCoarseLocation">approximate location
      (network-based)</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessCoarseLocation">Allows the app to get your
      approximate location. This location is derived by location services using
      network location sources such as cell towers and Wi-Fi. These location
      services must be turned on and available to your device for the app to
      use them. Apps may use this to determine approximately where you
      are.</string>
    <string name="permlab_modifyAudioSettings">change your audio settings</string>
    <string name="permdesc_modifyAudioSettings">Allows the app to modify global audio settings such as volume and which speaker is used for output.</string>
    <string name="permlab_recordAudio">record audio</string>
    <string name="permdesc_recordAudio">Allows the app to record audio with the
      microphone.  This permission allows the app to record audio at any time
      without your confirmation.</string>
    <string name="permlab_sim_communication">sim communication</string>
    <string name="permdesc_sim_communication">Allows the app to send commands to the SIM. This is very dangerous.</string>
    <string name="permlab_camera">Take pictures and videos</string>
    <string name="permdesc_camera">Allows the app to take pictures and videos
      with the camera.  This permission allows the app to use the camera at any
      time without your confirmation.</string>
    <string name="permlab_vibrate">control vibration</string>
    <string name="permdesc_vibrate">Allows the app to control the vibrator.</string>
    <string name="permlab_flashlight">control flashlight</string>
    <string name="permdesc_flashlight">Allows the app to control the flashlight.</string>
    <string name="permlab_callPhone">directly call phone numbers</string>
    <string name="permdesc_callPhone">Allows the app to call phone numbers
      without your intervention. This may result in unexpected charges or calls.
      Note that this doesn\'t allow the app to call emergency numbers.
      Malicious apps may cost you money by making calls without your
      confirmation.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessImsCallService">access IMS call service</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessImsCallService">Allows the app to use the IMS service to make calls without your intervention.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readPhoneState">read phone status and identity</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readPhoneState">Allows the app to access the phone
      features of the device.  This permission allows the app to determine the
      phone number and device IDs, whether a call is active, and the remote number
      connected by a call.</string>
    <string name="permlab_wakeLock">prevent phone from sleeping</string>
    <string name="permdesc_wakeLock">Allows the app to prevent the phone from going to sleep.</string>
    <string name="permlab_transmitIr">transmit infrared</string>
    <string name="permdesc_transmitIr">Allows the app to use the phone\'s infrared transmitter.</string>
    <string name="permlab_setWallpaper">set wallpaper</string>
    <string name="permdesc_setWallpaper">Allows the app to set the system wallpaper.</string>
    <string name="permlab_setWallpaperHints">adjust your wallpaper size</string>
    <string name="permdesc_setWallpaperHints">Allows the app to set the system wallpaper size hints.</string>
    <string name="permlab_setTimeZone">set time zone</string>
    <string name="permdesc_setTimeZone">Allows the app to change the phone\'s time zone.</string>
    <string name="permlab_getAccounts">find accounts on the device</string>
    <string name="permdesc_getAccounts">Allows the app to get
      the list of accounts known by the phone.  This may include any accounts
      created by applications you have installed.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessNetworkState">view network connections</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessNetworkState">Allows the app to view
      information about network connections such as which networks exist and are
      connected.</string>
    <string name="permlab_createNetworkSockets">full network access</string>
    <string name="permdesc_createNetworkSockets">Allows the app to create
     network sockets and use custom network protocols. The browser and other
     applications provide means to send data to the internet, so this
     permission is not required to send data to the internet.</string>
    <string name="permlab_changeNetworkState">change network connectivity</string>
    <string name="permdesc_changeNetworkState">Allows the app to change the state of network connectivity.</string>
    <string name="permlab_changeTetherState">change tethered connectivity</string>
    <string name="permdesc_changeTetherState">Allows the app to change the state of tethered network connectivity.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessWifiState">view Wi-Fi connections</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessWifiState">Allows the app to view information
      about Wi-Fi networking, such as whether Wi-Fi is enabled and name of
      connected Wi-Fi devices.</string>
    <string name="permlab_changeWifiState">connect and disconnect from Wi-Fi</string>
    <string name="permdesc_changeWifiState">Allows the app to connect to and
      disconnect from Wi-Fi access points and to make changes to device
      configuration for Wi-Fi networks.</string>
    <string name="permlab_changeWifiMulticastState">allow Wi-Fi Multicast reception</string>
    <string name="permdesc_changeWifiMulticastState">Allows the app to receive
      packets sent to all devices on a Wi-Fi network using multicast addresses,
      not just your phone.  It uses more power than the non-multicast mode.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bluetoothAdmin">access Bluetooth settings</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bluetoothAdmin">Allows the app to configure
      the local Bluetooth phone, and to discover and pair with remote devices.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessWimaxState">connect and disconnect from WiMAX</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessWimaxState">Allows the app to determine whether
     WiMAX is enabled and information about any WiMAX networks that are
     connected. </string>
    <string name="permlab_changeWimaxState">Change WiMAX state</string>
    <string name="permdesc_changeWimaxState">Allows the app to
      connect the phone to and disconnect the phone from WiMAX networks.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bluetooth">pair with Bluetooth devices</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bluetooth">Allows the app to view the
      configuration of the Bluetooth on the phone, and to make and accept
      connections with paired devices.</string>
    <string name="permlab_nfc">control Near Field Communication</string>
    <string name="permdesc_nfc">Allows the app to communicate
      with Near Field Communication (NFC) tags, cards, and readers.</string>
    <string name="permlab_disableKeyguard">disable your screen lock</string>
    <string name="permdesc_disableKeyguard">Allows the app to disable the
      keylock and any associated password security.  For example, the phone
      disables the keylock when receiving an incoming phone call, then
      re-enables the keylock when the call is finished.</string>
    <string name="permlab_manageFingerprint">manage fingerprint hardware</string>
    <string name="permdesc_manageFingerprint">Allows the app to invoke methods to add and delete fingerprint templates for use.</string>
    <string name="permlab_useFingerprint">use fingerprint hardware</string>
    <string name="permdesc_useFingerprint">Allows the app to use fingerprint hardware for authentication</string>
    <string name="permlab_readSyncSettings">read sync settings</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readSyncSettings">Allows the app to read the sync settings for an account. For example, this can determine whether the People app is synced with an account.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeSyncSettings">toggle sync on and off</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeSyncSettings">Allows an app to modify the sync settings for an account.  For example, this can be used to enable sync of the People app with an account.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readSyncStats">read sync statistics</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readSyncStats">Allows an app to read the sync stats for an account, including the history of sync events and how much data is synced. </string>
    <string name="permlab_sdcardRead">read the contents of your SD card</string>
    <string name="permdesc_sdcardRead">Allows the app to read the contents of your SD card.</string>
    <string name="permlab_sdcardWrite">modify or delete the contents of your SD card</string>
    <string name="permdesc_sdcardWrite">Allows the app to write to the SD card.</string>
    <string name="permlab_use_sip">make/receive SIP calls</string>
    <string name="permdesc_use_sip">Allows the app to make and receive SIP calls.</string>
    <string name="permlab_register_sim_subscription">register new telecom SIM connections</string>
    <string name="permdesc_register_sim_subscription">Allows the app to register new telecom SIM connections.</string>
    <string name="permlab_register_call_provider">register new telecom connections</string>
    <string name="permdesc_register_call_provider">Allows the app to register new telecom connections.</string>
    <string name="permlab_connection_manager">manage telecom connections</string>
    <string name="permdesc_connection_manager">Allows the app to manage telecom connections.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bind_incall_service">interact with in-call screen</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bind_incall_service">Allows the app to control when and how the user sees the in-call screen.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bind_connection_service">interact with telephony services</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bind_connection_service">Allows the app to interact with telephony services to make/receive calls.</string>
    <string name="permlab_control_incall_experience">provide an in-call user experience</string>
    <string name="permdesc_control_incall_experience">Allows the app to provide an in-call user experience.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readNetworkUsageHistory">read historical network usage</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readNetworkUsageHistory">Allows the app to read historical network usage for specific networks and apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_manageNetworkPolicy">manage network policy</string>
    <string name="permdesc_manageNetworkPolicy">Allows the app to manage network policies and define app-specific rules.</string>
    <string name="permlab_modifyNetworkAccounting">modify network usage accounting</string>
    <string name="permdesc_modifyNetworkAccounting">Allows the app to modify how network usage is accounted against apps. Not for use by normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessNotifications">access notifications</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessNotifications">Allows the app to retrieve, examine, and clear notifications, including those posted by other apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bindNotificationListenerService">bind to a notification listener service</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bindNotificationListenerService">Allows the holder to bind to the top-level interface of a notification listener service. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bindConditionProviderService">bind to a condition provider service</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bindConditionProviderService">Allows the holder to bind to the top-level interface of a condition provider service. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bindDreamService">bind to a dream service</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bindDreamService">Allows the holder to bind to the top-level interface of a dream service. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_invokeCarrierSetup">invoke the carrier-provided configuration app</string>
    <string name="permdesc_invokeCarrierSetup">Allows the holder to invoke the carrier-provided configuration app. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessNetworkConditions">listen for observations on network conditions</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessNetworkConditions">Allows an application to listen for observations on network conditions. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_setInputCalibration">change input device calibration</string>
    <string name="permdesc_setInputCalibration">Allows the app to modify the calibration parameters of the touch screen. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_accessDrmCertificates">access DRM certificates</string>
    <string name="permdesc_accessDrmCertificates">Allows an application to provision and use DRM certficates. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_handoverStatus">Receive Android Beam transfer status</string>
    <string name="permdesc_handoverStatus">Allows this application to receive information about current Android Beam transfers</string>
    <string name="permlab_removeDrmCertificates">remove DRM certificates</string>
    <string name="permdesc_removeDrmCertificates">Allows an application to remove DRM certficates. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bindCarrierMessagingService">bind to a carrier messaging service</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bindCarrierMessagingService">Allows the holder to bind to the top-level interface of a carrier messaging service. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_bindCarrierServices">bind to carrier services</string>
    <string name="permdesc_bindCarrierServices">Allows the holder to bind to carrier services. Should never be needed for normal apps.</string>
    <string name="permlab_access_notification_policy">access Do Not Disturb</string>
    <string name="permdesc_access_notification_policy">Allows the app to read and write Do Not Disturb configuration.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readHistoryBookmarks">read your Web bookmarks and history</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readHistoryBookmarks">Allows the app to read the
     history of all URLs that the Browser has visited, and all of the Browser\'s
     bookmarks. Note: this permission may not be enforced by third-party
     browsers or other  applications with web browsing capabilities.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeHistoryBookmarks">write web bookmarks and history</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeHistoryBookmarks">Allows the
        app to modify the Browser\'s history or bookmarks stored on your phone.
        This may allow the app to erase or modify Browser data.  Note:
        this permission may note be enforced by third-party browsers or other
        applications with web browsing capabilities.</string>
    <string name="permlab_setAlarm">set an alarm</string>
    <string name="permdesc_setAlarm">Allows the app to set an alarm in
        an installed alarm clock app. Some alarm clock apps may
        not implement this feature.</string>
    <string name="permlab_addVoicemail">add voicemail</string>
    <string name="permdesc_addVoicemail">Allows the app to add messages
      to your voicemail inbox.</string>
    <string name="permlab_writeGeolocationPermissions">modify Browser geolocation permissions</string>
    <string name="permdesc_writeGeolocationPermissions">Allows the app to modify the
        Browser\'s geolocation permissions. Malicious apps
        may use this to allow sending location information to arbitrary web sites.</string>
    <string name="permlab_route_media_output">Route media output</string>
    <string name="permdesc_route_media_output">Allows an application to route media output to other external devices.</string>
    <string name="permlab_readInstallSessions">Read install sessions</string>
    <string name="permdesc_readInstallSessions">Allows an application to read install sessions. This allows it to see details about active package installations.</string>
    <string name="permlab_requestInstallPackages">Request install packages</string>
    <string name="permdesc_requestInstallPackages">Allows an application to request installation of packages.</string>
</permission-info>
